mynetdiary.com 2016-03-16

# About MyNetDiary - Online Diet Log and iPhone Calorie Counter | MyNetDiary

## Overview

MyNetDiary.com understands the importance of privacy to our users. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the products, services and web sites offered by MyNetDiary.com. Where additional detailed information is needed to explain our privacy practices, we post supplementary privacy notices to describe how particular services process personal information. This Privacy Policy will tell you what information MyNetDiary.com collects about you and about your use of MyNetDiary.com and its services. We urge you to read this Privacy Policy carefully. 

By using MyNetDiary.com and our web sites, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should not use our web site. Your continued use of our web site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept those changes. 

##  Information Collection and Use

### Personal Information

#### General

MyNetDiary.com collects personal information when you visit MyNetDiary.com web pages and when you open an account with MyNetDiary.com or use other MyNetDiary.com products or services. MyNetDiary.com may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. We use information for the following general purposes: providing products and services, billing, identification and authentication, improving our services and web site, and contacting users and research. We aggregate certain information to develop statistics related to the use of MyNetDiary.com. We may publish some statistics based on aggregated information, but none of these statistics will contain any personally identifiable information. 

When you register to open an account with MyNetDiary.com, we ask for information such as your name, e-mail address, date of birth, gender, weight and height. To purchase certain products and services from MyNetDiary.com, we also ask you to provide other contact and billing information. MyNetDiary.com shares personally identifiable information only when required to complete your order. We do not otherwise share personally identifiable information with any third parties. 

Depending on the product or service you have selected, we may also collect certain personal information, including personal foods, activities and body measurements. Recognizing the highly personal nature of this information, we take special precautions to protect such information. 

Before and After photos taken on a mobile device are stored on the mobile device unencrypted. 

#### Credit Card Information

We use PayPal to process credit card transactions. You may choose to pay for your MyNetDiary.com account using any payment method accepted by PayPal. If you use PayPal to make a payment, we do not receive or store any credit card information. You may also choose to enter credit card information on MyNetDiary.com. If you provide your credit card information on our web site, we will store such information for the duration of the transaction until your credit card is charged and the requested product or service has been purchased. After the transaction is complete, we delete your credit card number and expiration date from our database. For convenience, we may store your billing address for use during future transactions. 

#### Fitness and Activity Data

We use fitness and activity data, including data provided by third-party activity trackers, to provide, personalize and improve your experience on the MyNetDiary.com website and in mobile applications. We may release or share Fitness and Activity Data with third parties in anonymous form and/or in the aggregate, for statistical analysis, research, demographic profiling and other similar purposes. 

#### Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service, we will ask you to provide an email address for the person you choose to refer. This email address is stored for the sole purpose of crediting your account when such person opens a new account with MyNetDiary.com and, if requested by you, for sending a one-time email to such individual upon making the referral. We will not use this email address for any other purposes and will not share it with any third parties. 

#### Message Boards and Other Public Forums

As a service to our users, MyNetDiary.com features message boards, online discussions, group and personal messages, and other public forums where users can share information or post questions for experts to answer. We offer certain online discussions moderated by dietitians and other health professionals. Any information (including personal information) that you reveal in a message board, online discussion, group or personal message, or other public forum is by design open to the public and is not a private, secure service. You should think carefully before disclosing any personally identifiable information in any public forum. What you have disclosed in such locations may be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes. As with any public forum on any site, this information may also appear in third-party search engines like Google, Yahoo, etc. 

#### Children

MyNetDiary.com is committed to protecting the privacy of children. The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use and disclose personal information from children under the age of 13. Neither MyNetDiary.com nor any of its services or products are designed or intended to attract children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is under the age of 13. COPPA requires that we obtain the consent of parents or guardians before collecting, using or disclosing personal information from children under the age of 13. 

In compliance with COPPA, a parent or guardian may request to review, delete or stop the collection of personally identifiable information relating to their child or any child in their legal custody who is under the age of 13. Parents or guardians may review, delete or stop the collection of personally identifiable information by contacting us by letter, phone or email using the contact information provided in this Privacy Policy. 

A parent or guardian may use MyNetDiary.com to establish an account for a minor. The parent or guardian is solely responsible for providing supervision of the minor's use of MyNetDiary.com. The parent or guardian assumes full responsibility for ensuring that the registration information is kept secure and that the information submitted is accurate. The parent or guardian also assumes full responsibility for the interpretation and use of any information or suggestions provided through MyNetDiary.com for the minor. 

### Non-Personal Information

#### General

Even if you do not register with MyNetDiary.com, we collect non-personal information about your use of our web site, special promotions and other services. 

#### Cookies

We collect non-personal information about your use of our web site. Every computer that accesses a MyNetDiary.com web site is assigned different Cookies by MyNetDiary.com. Cookies are required for the use of certain MyNetDiary.com services. The information collected by Cookies (i) records current session information, (ii) allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our web site, (iii) how many people open our emails, (iv) web sites referring visitors to us, and (iv) for what purposes these actions are being taken. We may use Cookie information to determine the popularity of certain content, advertisements, and effectiveness of our marketing programs. Cookies are also used to facilitate a user's log-in. 

Most browser software can be set to reject all Cookies. Additionally, most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject Cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. If you reject our Cookies, the member section of our web site may not work properly, but you do not have to accept our Cookies in order to use our public information available without becoming a member of our site. We do not use Cookies to collect or store personal information about you. 

#### Access Logs

MyNetDiary.com automatically collects certain information and stores it in log files, including internet protocol (IP) addresses, referring/exit pages, operating system, browser type, date/time stamp and clickstream data. We use this non-personal information, to analyze trends, to administer our web site and to gather demographic information about our user base. We also record your IP address with your personally identifiable information to help protect ourselves and our members from abusive users of our web site. 

## Links to Other Sites

The MyNetDiary.com web site contains links to other web sites. We do not provide any personally identifiable information to these third party web sites. Once you enter another web site (whether through an advertisement, service or content link), be aware that MyNetDiary.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy policy of each and every web site that you visit through a link or advertisement on MyNetDiary.com. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by MyNetDiary.com. 

## Disclosure of Information

Except as described in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, MyNetDiary.com will not disclose any personally identifiable information it gathers from you on our web site. We may only release personally identifiable information to third parties to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order or, as deemed necessary in MyNetDiary.com's discretion, to protect the legal or property rights of MyNetDiary.com, a user or third party, or to prevent personal injury. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your personally identifiable information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. 

## Security, Encryption and Confidentiality

MyNetDiary.com uses industry-standard encryption technology to protect your privacy. We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with such information to provide products or services to you in order to do their jobs. We have physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect personal information about you. 

We utilize Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption in transmitting your personally identifiable information to our servers. In order to take advantage of encryption technology, you must have an internet browser which supports 128-bit encryption. 

It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. You will be required to sign in to your MyNetDiary.com account after a certain period of time has elapsed to protect you against others accidentally accessing your account. 

### Data Storage

MyNetDiary.com uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage and related technology required to operate MyNetDiary.com. The MyNetDiary.com database is stored on secured servers owned and operated by MyNetDiary Inc. We may store encrypted database backups off site with a third party storage provider to ensure data security in the case of an emergency or catastrophe. 

## Business Transitions

If MyNetDiary.com is acquired by or merges with another company, the assets of our web sites, including personal information, will likely be transferred to the new company. 

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

MyNetDiary.com may update this Privacy Policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your MyNetDiary.com account or by placing a prominent notice on our web site. MyNetDiary.com may make non-significant changes to the Privacy Policy. For these instances, MyNetDiary.com may not notify you of such non-significant changes. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy and other appropriate places throughout our web site so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. 

## Access to your Personal Information

You can access the personal information you submit to our web site at any time. If you wish to change, update or delete the personal information you have submitted to us, you may do so by signing into your account on the web site or by sending an email to support@mynetdiary.com with your request. 

## Removal

You may remove your personally identifiable information from our systems, as well as all MyNetDiary.com communications and promotions by contacting us through one of the following methods: 

        Email:	Send an email to opt-out@mynetdiary.com

        Mail:	MyNetDiary Inc.
                Opt-Out List
                811 Church Road, Suite 105
                Cherry Hill, New Jersey 08002

## Contacting MyNetDiary.com

If you have a privacy concern or question regarding MyNetDiary.com or this Privacy Policy and if you cannot satisfactorily resolve it through the use of our web site, you should contact us through one of the following methods: 

        Email:	Send an email to support@mynetdiary.com

        Mail:	MyNetDiary Inc.
                811 Church Road, Suite 105
                Cherry Hill, New Jersey 08002
